<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Smccoy's Snacks]]></title><description><![CDATA[A short recipe book in honor of Smccoy's 21st birthday!]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoy-snacks/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 05:31:56 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Sara's Summer Salad]]></title><description><![CDATA[A fresh choice for a warm summer day!Throw this together in a 10 minutes or less and you’ll be on your way.Recipe:NotesYou could totally use…]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoy-snacks//saras-summer-salad/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoy-snacks//saras-summer-salad/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;A fresh choice for a warm summer day!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throw this together in a 10 minutes or less and you’ll be on your way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recipe:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add however much &lt;strong&gt;spinach&lt;/strong&gt; you want to a bowl&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top with some &lt;strong&gt;quinoa&lt;/strong&gt; (best cold)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Throw in some chopped &lt;strong&gt;strawberries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chop up some &lt;strong&gt;almonds&lt;/strong&gt; or really any other nut and throw them in. They&apos;re best if roasted. Just toss the nuts in a pan and heat them until golden. No need to add any oil or anything unless you want to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goat cheese!&lt;/strong&gt; Add goat cheese crumbles. A great option is the Trader Joe&apos;s Honey Chevre.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a quick &lt;strong&gt;dressing&lt;/strong&gt;. Combine balsamic vinegar, honey or maple syrup, a dash of salt, and a little olive oil in a small mason jar or something. Shake it well to combine. Pour into your salad, mix it up a little, and you&apos;re good to go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could totally use this as a salad template. For example, you could swap out the strawberries for peaches. Or use feta instead of goat cheese and make it more of a savory salad with more veggies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    “Car rides to Malibu. Strawerry ice cream, one spoon for two.&quot; (Rodrigo, 2021).
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dw's Pasta Carbonara]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’m not going to copy and paste someone else’s recipe here because that would be a copyright violation, but I will advocate for this dish.I…]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoy-snacks//pasta-carbonara/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoy-snacks//pasta-carbonara/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to copy and paste someone else’s recipe here because that would be a copyright violation, but I will advocate for this dish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;hate&lt;/em&gt; undercooked eggs (“over hard please!”) so I was terrified to try this dish. However, you cannot even tell there’s eggs in it because they get lost in the cheesy sauce. Dwlbo really wanted me to try this and I’m so glad we did end up making it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a cheap meal that you can make feel super fancy. Pair it with wine and you’ve got yourself a girls night! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally it has bacon in it, but you could easily exclude that and use peas instead (pea protein hollaaa). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Search the interwebs for “pasta carbonara recipe” and you’ll get about 35 million results——plenty to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &quot;My running&apos;s so-so, but I&apos;m one of the nation&apos;s top five carbo-loaders&quot; (the first Google Images result for &quot;quotes about carbo loading&quot;).
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Benji's Breakfast Bash]]></title><description><![CDATA[Benji eats this way too often.(Like almost everday.)And in turn, I am quite familiar with this. I discovered it is fantastic post-run fuel…]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoy-snacks//benji-breakfast/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoy-snacks//benji-breakfast/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Benji eats this way too often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Like almost everday.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in turn, I am quite familiar with this. I discovered it is fantastic post-run fuel. So salty and protein-y and healthy fatty and yummy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What you’ll need &amp;#x26; what to do:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chop &lt;strong&gt;onion&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;bell peppers&lt;/strong&gt; and start sauteing them in a little oil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add one &lt;strong&gt;Trader Joe’s Hash Brown&lt;/strong&gt; (per person eating) to the pan (or in a separate pan, whatever works. Everything will end up in the same pan in the end.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the same with &lt;strong&gt;vegan sausage&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As everything softens up, use your spatula to break the hashbrowns and vegan sauasage into small chunks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once that onions and bell peppers are cooked to your liking, and the hashbrowns are golden brown, add in your &lt;strong&gt;eggs&lt;/strong&gt;. You probably only need 1-2 eggs per person because the hashbrowns bulk this up a bit. Mix everything together as a scramble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;strong&gt;salt&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;pepper&lt;/strong&gt; while the eggs are cooking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top with &lt;strong&gt;avocado&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;fresh cilantro&lt;/strong&gt;. Remember to fold your cilantro in half or thirds before you start chopping. This is more efficient and helps you get a finer chop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optional: top with &lt;strong&gt;salsa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throw it in small or large torillas and make it a burrito or tacos. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blissful Baked Beans]]></title><description><![CDATA[RecipeOpen a can of pinto beans and rinse them in a strainer.Throw them on a pan and let it get up to medium heat.Once the pan is…]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoy-snacks//beans/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoy-snacks//beans/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Recipe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open a can of &lt;strong&gt;pinto beans&lt;/strong&gt; and rinse them in a strainer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throw them on a pan and let it get up to medium heat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once the pan is sufficiently hot, throw in a bunch of &lt;strong&gt;coconut aminos&lt;/strong&gt;. You want the end product to have a bit of a suacy feel (like baked beans) but also need to recognize that some of the coconut aminos will burn off due to the heat. So you want to monitor the heat to balance these needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the liquid is looking too thin, you can add a tablespoon or so of flour or cornstarch to thicken it up a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose some sort of spice. You don’t need to make it spicy, but you need something to complement the sweetness of the coconut aminos and add flavor. &lt;strong&gt;Chile paste&lt;/strong&gt; or any sort of &lt;strong&gt;paprika&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;chile powder&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;chile flakes&lt;/strong&gt;, etc will do the trick. Add &lt;strong&gt;salt&lt;/strong&gt; too, of course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serve over &lt;strong&gt;brown rice&lt;/strong&gt;, and top with &lt;strong&gt;diced tomatoes&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;fresh cilantro&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;avodaco&lt;/strong&gt; if you wish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    “Beans beans the magical fruit. The more you eat, the more you toot&quot; (Unknown children&apos;s song, early 2000s?)
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Power Protein Pancakes]]></title><description><![CDATA[Y’all Kodiac Cakes are amazing, but hecka expensive. I “developed” this recipe over time as I kept making pancakes from scratch because I…]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoy-snacks//Power Protein Pancakes/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoy-snacks//Power Protein Pancakes/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Y’all Kodiac Cakes are amazing, but hecka expensive. I “developed” this recipe over time as I kept making pancakes from scratch because I didn’t want to spend $$ on the mix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recipe (feeds two)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose one or two bowls you can mix things in. You don’t have to mix the dry and wet ingredients separately (I usually don’t, however, this usually leads to more clumps). Ideally, you would use a large measuring cup that has a small spout so that it is less messy when you start pouring batter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combine &lt;strong&gt;one cup of flour&lt;/strong&gt; with a couple of teaspoons or so of baking powder. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add in &lt;strong&gt;two beaten eggs&lt;/strong&gt; and a solid amount of &lt;strong&gt;milk&lt;/strong&gt;. Use whatever type of milk you have on hand, they’ll all work. I mix with a rubber spatula/scraper because this will be useful later when you’re trying to get one more pancake out of what’s sticking to the sides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep adding liquid until you get the desired pancake batter consistency. It should be pretty thin, but not too thin to where you’ll end up with crepes! I usually switch to &lt;strong&gt;water&lt;/strong&gt; at some point. In my experience, using only milk as liquid can result in somewhat gooey/doughy pancake centers since milk is thicker than water.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you have the consistency right, choose your flavor. You might add &lt;strong&gt;chocolate chips&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;blueberries&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;cinnamon&lt;/strong&gt;, or whatever your heart desires.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat a pan to medium heat and get your pancake flipping on! If you added mix-ins, be sure to mix the batter around before each pour, otherwise everything will end up in the last pancake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serve with &lt;strong&gt;butter&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;maple syrup&lt;/strong&gt;. (And coffee + fruit salad pairs really well too :P)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &quot;Everything can have drama if it&apos;s done right. Even a pancake&quot; (Julia Child).
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hen's Tasty Tilapia]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ida and Evan (Hen’s cats) are hungry for some lemon pepper tilapia.This recipe is from Hen’s family. He knows everything about fish and…]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoy-snacks//Hen&apos;s Tasty Tilapia/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoy-snacks//Hen&apos;s Tasty Tilapia/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Ida and Evan (Hen’s cats) are hungry for some lemon pepper tilapia.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recipe is from Hen’s family. He knows everything about fish and fishing. He only eats buys sea fish because store bought lake fish isn’t good enough for him, since he knows how it tastes fresh. Also, I’m pretty sure tilapia is pretty cheap at the store (don’t quote me on that though). Anywho, tilapia makes the cut, so here’s the fam recipe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Baked Lemon Pepper Tilapia for Four&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat oven to 375&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coat bottom of 9x13 pan with &lt;strong&gt;spray grease&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lay filets (3) in the pan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sprinkle with &lt;strong&gt;Seafood Magic&lt;/strong&gt; seasoning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put a pat of &lt;strong&gt;butter&lt;/strong&gt; and slice of &lt;strong&gt;lemon&lt;/strong&gt; on each&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cover with foil for half of the time, then uncover for the other half&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cook 30-35 minutes until flakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you what it means for tilapia to flake. Maybe this is an opportunity for you to practice your eyeballing skills! Or maybe best to not practice with fish…? Maybe Gary can help with this one. Also, I don’t see where the pepper comes in. That is up to you to experiment with!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    “To improve taste and odor place a slice of lemon in your water...” (City of Phoenix, FAQ).
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Message from Mandy]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sara,I seriously cannot believe you are 21! SO grown! Seems like yesterday you were a lil freshman running around Elder and bonding over…]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoy-snacks//Message from Mandy/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoy-snacks//Message from Mandy/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Sara,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I seriously cannot believe you are 21! SO grown! Seems like yesterday you were a lil freshman running around Elder and bonding over movie nights during preseason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh how we’ve grown since then! I know that I have personally grown so much as a direct result of being your friend. I am grateful for all of the convos, runs, and Thanksgivings. I don’t really know how to put into words how it has been a crazy three years and through the good moments (Boston!) and bad (Azusa/Longbeach!) we have been by each other’s sides, supported one another, and kept each other sane. I truly cherish our friendship and hope we get to visit each other often as we both soon enter the next phase of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You inspire me in more ways than you know. I hope I inspire you with some more meal ideas here :P Take care of yourself, inside and out, with some nourishing, tasty food, and the people who adore you, and you’ll be alright. Hope you enjoy. Visit me in Idaho thx!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;xoxo
Mandy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/smccoy-snacks/static/a824ffecdcf8b1ea7497cc93530b7634/22db8/buds.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin: 7vw 0; max-width: 1360px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 133.10344827586206%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAbABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAGAABAAMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIDBAX/xAAWAQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAAL/2gAMAwEAAhADEAAAAXM0QzrOkS2qydYwn//EABwQAAICAwEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECABEDIjEEMv/aAAgBAQABBQL0rvVyysDxKLZDswUY0BEYm83V+W7/AP/EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAB/9oACAEDAQE/ASn/xAAVEQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQAf/aAAgBAgEBPwEh/8QAHBAAAgICAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERIRAgMUFx/9oACAEBAAY/Aul4QuSGi82rJWv/xAAcEAACAwADAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREhMUFRgbH/2gAIAQEAAT8hxLATf1GAMdch2e2IUUi4MsY6wGJtjunBTwj4H//aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQ999N/8QAFxEBAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQAhEf/aAAgBAwEBPxAB5ONhy7f/xAAXEQADAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAASER/9oACAECAQE/ENaFSlTD/8QAHhABAAMAAgIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAQARITFBcaFhsfH/2gAIAQEAAT8Q2VQH5RojK2eJdUQ8pGWsQst7hmPdZ7iRWG+Zcw14ZcaJasssb/IwsruFRwbgKJgDLX1OPw+p/9k=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;picture&gt;
        &lt;source
          srcset=&quot;/smccoy-snacks/static/a824ffecdcf8b1ea7497cc93530b7634/53e9f/buds.webp 340w,
/smccoy-snacks/static/a824ffecdcf8b1ea7497cc93530b7634/0991f/buds.webp 680w,
/smccoy-snacks/static/a824ffecdcf8b1ea7497cc93530b7634/9d77c/buds.webp 1360w,
/smccoy-snacks/static/a824ffecdcf8b1ea7497cc93530b7634/27063/buds.webp 2040w,
/smccoy-snacks/static/a824ffecdcf8b1ea7497cc93530b7634/89e6f/buds.webp 2320w&quot;
          sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1360px) 100vw, 1360px&quot;
          type=&quot;image/webp&quot;
        /&gt;
        &lt;source
          srcset=&quot;/smccoy-snacks/static/a824ffecdcf8b1ea7497cc93530b7634/a0703/buds.jpg 340w,
/smccoy-snacks/static/a824ffecdcf8b1ea7497cc93530b7634/5041d/buds.jpg 680w,
/smccoy-snacks/static/a824ffecdcf8b1ea7497cc93530b7634/fe1b8/buds.jpg 1360w,
/smccoy-snacks/static/a824ffecdcf8b1ea7497cc93530b7634/25fce/buds.jpg 2040w,
/smccoy-snacks/static/a824ffecdcf8b1ea7497cc93530b7634/22db8/buds.jpg 2320w&quot;
          sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1360px) 100vw, 1360px&quot;
          type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot;
        /&gt;
        &lt;img
          class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
          style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
          src=&quot;/smccoy-snacks/static/a824ffecdcf8b1ea7497cc93530b7634/fe1b8/buds.jpg&quot;
          alt=&quot;sara-and-mandy&quot;
          title=&quot;&quot;
          src=&quot;/smccoy-snacks/static/a824ffecdcf8b1ea7497cc93530b7634/fe1b8/buds.jpg&quot;
        /&gt;
      &lt;/picture&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>