<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Smccoy's Snacks]]></title><description><![CDATA[A short recipe book in honor of Smccoy's 21st birthday!]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoys-snacks/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 15:40:53 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Sara's Summer Salad]]></title><description><![CDATA[(1) A glaring symbol of unequal access to opportunity that can be seen from the sky.(2) A path on which a person is placed that will…]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoys-snacks//saras-summer-salad/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoys-snacks//saras-summer-salad/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;(1) A glaring symbol of unequal access to opportunity that can be seen from the sky.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;(2) A path on which a person is placed that will influence certain outcomes in their life.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rickey Gates blah blah blah. The essay takes form through four chapters and an epilogue, and includes many, many photos. Several of the photos are original, either taken by myself or one of my parents. This is purposeful for multiple reasons. Firstly, as the author, I am so closely tied to the subject that it would be impossible to escape any bias I have towards the subject, so in a creative choice, I decided to go to the one extreme, which is to be unabashedly honest about my connection to the topic. Thus, I attempt, with my utmost effort, to share how I view water in the desert through my own eyes. Secondly, Phoenix’s water is what quite literally sustained me for the first 18 years of my life. I have lived the rare experience of returning to the same home my parents returned to from the hospital with my newborn self as when I came home after my high school graduation ceremony. The same pipes, the same tap, have always hydrated me, and for so long I took it for granted. This is a tribute to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Arizona&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Desert Vista High School, Phoenix, AZ&lt;/h3&gt;
 &lt;h2 id=&quot;table&quot;&gt;Table&lt;/h2&gt;
          &lt;table&gt;
            &lt;thead&gt;
              &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;Price&lt;/th&gt;
              &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;/thead&gt;
            &lt;tbody&gt;
              &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Item 1&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Ante turpis integer aliquet porttitor.&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;29.99&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;/tr&gt;
              &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Item 2&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Vis ac commodo adipiscing arcu aliquet.&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;19.99&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;/tr&gt;
              &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Item 3&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt; Morbi faucibus arcu accumsan lorem.&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;29.99&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;/tr&gt;
              &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Item 4&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Vitae integer tempus condimentum.&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;19.99&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;/tr&gt;
              &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Item 5&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Ante turpis integer aliquet porttitor.&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;29.99&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;/tbody&gt;
            &lt;tfoot&gt;
              &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td colSpan={2} /&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;100.00&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;/tfoot&gt;
          &lt;/table&gt;

          &lt;div
            class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot;
            style=&quot;padding-bottom: 75%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 1.0725rem&quot;
          &gt;
            &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d978.0886430973648!2d-112.01867988432143!3d33.29692201326605!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x0%3A0x0!2zMzPCsDE3JzQ5LjAiTiAxMTLCsDAxJzA1LjciVw!5e1!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1616815903445!5m2!1sen!2sus&quot; style=&quot;border:0;
            position: absolute;
            top: 0;
            left: 0;
            width: 100%;
            height: 100%;
          &quot; allowfullscreen loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
          
&lt;h3&gt;Mayer High School, Mayer, AZ&lt;/h3&gt;

          &lt;div
            class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot;
            style=&quot;padding-bottom: 75%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 1.0725rem&quot;
          &gt;
            &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d966.1418214113233!2d-112.15752971766432!3d34.347831965005426!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x872ce8ba56826851%3A0xab561b947bc28bf7!2s17300%20E%20Mule%20Deer%20Dr%2C%20Mayer%2C%20AZ%2086333!5e1!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1616815705800!5m2!1sen!2sus&quot; style=&quot;border:0;
            position: absolute;
            top: 0;
            left: 0;
            width: 100%;
            height: 100%;
          &quot; allowfullscreen loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
          
&lt;p&gt;The order of the four chapters roughly corresponds to the timeline of my consciousness with respect to the phenomenon of water in Phoenix. That is, towards the beginning there is a photo of me as a child in my Aunt’s swimming pool, whereas the ending chapter is a case study about water on the Gila River Indian Reservation and is the most formally written of the four chapters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the reader: My hope is that you find this essay accessible, yet also artistically curious. Through these photos and words, I hope to communicate the complex relationship that exists between desert and water. At some moments, it seems ”desert” and  “water” are antonyms; in other moments, the two are inextricable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    “A cactus doesn&apos;t live in the desert because it likes the desert; it lives there because the desert hasn&apos;t killed it yet&quot; (Jahren, 2017).
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Note About Images&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All images on this website are used according to copyright law. Images are either part of the public domain, creative commons, qualify for educational fair use, or were produced by the author or her family. Thank you to my parents for going on a couple of extra walks to send me some of the content included in this essay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jahren, Hope. Lab girl. HarperCollins Brasil, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dw's Pasta Carbonara]]></title><description><![CDATA[{Google Maps screenshot of a few streets near my house in which every backyard has a pool}PoolsEveryone in my immediate neighborhood has a…]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoys-snacks//pasta-carbonara/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoys-snacks//pasta-carbonara/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h6&gt;{Google Maps screenshot of a few streets near my house in which every backyard has a pool}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone in my immediate neighborhood has a pool, as far as I can tell. If not every last house, then nearly every last house. If your home is in middle-to-upper-class suburban Phoenix and you do not have a pool, you fear a decrease in the resale value. My house has a pool. Technically, it’s a “swim-spa” because it is only four-feet deep all around and just 14 feet long. Fourteen feet may sound sizeable, but in comparison to an average Phoenix suburban pool, that’s quite small. My pool is outfitted with a heater and jets; the jets are designed to allow a person to swim in place against the current in this tiny pool. My dad once tore his meniscus doing just that. In fact, my dad pretty much wants the pool gone, and not just because it caused his meniscus to tear. The pool requires a lot of upkeep. However, draining and then filling a pool in with concrete is an expensive ordeal—almost as expensive as building a brand-new pool. Plus, my dad is on the verge of retirement. If he might be selling the house in a couple of years, what’s the use? Any young, Arizona family or snowbird couple will seek out a house with a pool for the kids or grandkids. Getting rid of a pool in Arizona is borderline Desert Blasphemy. My family and I have hardly used our pool since my brother and I graduated from middle school, but the pool is there to stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up in Arizona, part of the culture is pool culture. And while I write this from my middle-to-upper-class suburban perspective, I have observed that pool culture permeates class lines. While the form of the pool might change, the fact that there is a pool remains constant. I recall flying into Phoenix’s Sky Harbor Airport once, noticing a common appendage to the small homes in lower-class areas of Phoenix. In the yards of most of these homes were those small, circular blow-up or plastic kiddy pools. Their circular shape was unmistakable from the sky. So, when I say there is a “pool culture” in Phoenix, I mean that, as I was growing up, I went to who-knows-how-many pool parties to celebrate my friends’ birthdays. That I learned how to swim in my own backyard and so did my dog (or at least he tried). That when girls get older and begin succumbing to the expectations of social media, they post endless photos of themselves seductively posing by the poolside in bikinis. That in my neighborhood, there are three “community pools” maintained by the home-owners association, meaning that if there is a park, there is likely to be a pool accompanying it. That in middle school I remember going to the local waterpark with my neighborhood friend and getting 7/11 slushies afterwards. Pools, to me growing up, were a given, like a natural resource that is plentiful. Pools have always been there and always will be. A fact of life for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;{Mandy as a child, swimming in her Aunt’s pool in Paradise Valley, AZ}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./mandy_in_pool.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Pools-ponds-lawns&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ponds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always hated ponds. To me, ponds were always associated with fakeness. Ponds were collections of water placed in places they weren’t supposed to be. Their water was a color of blue that I knew was incorrect. The fountain at their middle was so manufactured that it made me despise the water the pond held. The ponds along the greenbelt, the large ponds in the Lakewood neighborhood made it excessively clear that the place I lived in was perfectly developed, intricately manicured, and filled with things that weren’t meant to be there: palm trees brought in from California, lush grass, and blue-dyed water pumped in from who-knows-where. Those ponds made me feel like I was in the 2012 version of the Lorax, living in Thneedville with its electric trees, like the Oak-a-Matic. I longed to live somewhere that had &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; trees and &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; water. I didn’t yet understand the allure of the desert. I also certainly did not understand the possibility that water can be naturally abundant in a desert, though that seems to be a contradiction. Water was something imported, not found. Water was poured into concrete pools, or ponds—bigger concrete pools. Water in the desert isn’t &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lawns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;{The new water-efficient sprinklers in my backyard. One of my more vivid memories from my childhood is an intense argument between my parents about whether we should plant winter grass in the backyard.}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./sprinkler.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Pools-ponds-lawns&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worst of all, I associated ponds with golf courses. Golf courses were the epitome of desert falsehood. They combined all the fabricated components that I despised most: lush grass sustained by endless sprinkler systems, towering palm trees that are native to the California, not the Arizona desert, and so many ponds. Arizona has long been an attraction for winter golf, but two of the golf courses in my immediate area have been deserted in the past decade. They are now eyesores that consist of dying grass and empty concrete basins that were once ponds. It is as if the land has taken its makeup off. Now, the debates ensue—how about new condominiums? What about the homeowners who signed off on their property being told that their backyard would always face an operating golf course? To grow grass or not to grow grass, that is the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;{Hole #3 at The Golf Club at Dove Mountain, Marana, Arizona}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./golf_course.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;golf-course&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Bernard Gagnon, CC BY-SA 3.0 &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0&quot;&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0&lt;/a&gt;, via Wikimedia Commons)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./river_rocks_grass.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;river-rocks&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My front yard exhibits desert landscaping including a mesquite tree, prickly pear cactus, gravel, and river rocks. However, many homeowners in my neighborhood choose extravagantly verdant landscaping options. My backyard’s cinder block wall started crumbling as a result of the next-door-neighbor’s overwatering of his jungle-like backyard. Others find a middle ground, like the above photo of a neighbor’s lush grass bisected by the classic river rock design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./lake_bucci.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Pools-ponds-lawns&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though rare, big storms sometimes roll through Phoenix. Especially in the late summer, when Phoenix experiences monsoon season. These monsoons often entail a massive dust storm called a “haboob,” which is generally followed by a heavy rain. Whenever a large amount of water is deposited from the sky, it has a hard time soaking into the dirt and runs off the slick ground to collect in a low point. The above picture is evidence of the pond that forms in the bermuda grass park next to my high school. It might actually qualify as a lake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Desert’s Envy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They say the grass is always greener on the other side, but in the desert’s case, the grass is always greener if you plant it in the first place, and then subsequently barrage it with an inordinate amount of water. In the desert, you will find novelties such as the saguaro cacti that only exist within the bounds of the Sonoran desert. However, you will also find relics of Westward expansion’s nostalgia for the lush Eastern United States. In the desert, the social construction of nature is displayed quite literally, but physically speaking, is perhaps more of an actual construction, or importation of nature. Like when someone in New York City places a cactus in their windowsill. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The social construction of nature in this case is much more apparent in my own interpretation of this imported nature. I find myself, put bluntly, disgusted by this imported nature, like the golf course ponds, but only because my reference point consists of my socially constructed definition of nature. Growing up in Phoenix, I was somewhat offended that we would direct so many natural resources towards replicating natural features that were meant to be located in other regions. I felt the contrast between South Mountain Park—the seemingly untouched natural space beyond my house—and the manufactured suburban area that flanked its south side. The trails and roads that carve out South Mountain never got on my nerves, whereas concrete and asphalt sprinkled with plots of green and pools of bright blue certainly did. I now realize that my relative satisfaction with nature is socially constructed and dependent on obscuration. That is, if a feature does a good job at passing as natural, I will accept it and adore it. However, if a feature is visibly assembled by human intervention, I become frustrated and discount it as nature at all. Thus, if I was never introduced to the knowledge that the massive lakes resultant of dams were the outcome of manipulation, I would be in awe of their natural beauty. These lakes do a better job of mimicking my idea of nature than the ponds filled with ducks and fountains in my neighborhood, but even now I would never take a picture of the pond, whereas I would certainly be tempted to take a picture of the dam lake. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter how well they pull off the act, these “unnatural” features are representative of a desert ideal—a place with the mysticism of the desert but the ammenities of the forest. On the final page of his book &lt;em&gt;Dead Pool: Lake Powell, Global Warming, and the Future of Water in the West&lt;/em&gt;, James Powell asks, “can we save the desert civilization that [the dams] symbolize?” The alteration of natural resources is a visible signal of modernity and scientific progress. These engineering breakthroughs act as reassurance that our idealistic “desert civilization” is running smoothly. The desert is now calculated and planned. What could possibly go wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next chapter, I will transition back to “natural” features, for example, the naturally occurring Havasupai Falls, which is much more glorious than the miniature pool waterfalls that are abundant in my neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Powell, James Lawrence. Dead pool: Lake Powell, global warming, and the future of water in the West. Univ of California Press, 2008.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blissful 'Baked' Beans]]></title><description><![CDATA[{A topographic map of Phoenix, 1914, showing the Salt River, the Gila River, and multiple canals}havasupai-falls{Havasupai Falls}(User…]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoys-snacks//beans/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoys-snacks//beans/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h6&gt;{A topographic map of Phoenix, 1914, showing the Salt River, the Gila River, and multiple canals}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./havasupai_falls.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;havasupai-falls&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;{Havasupai Falls}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(User:Moondigger, CC BY-SA 2.5 &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5&quot;&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5&lt;/a&gt;, via Wikimedia Commons)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Havasupai people of Northern Arizona are well-known around the world as a result of one waterfall that is located on their land: Havasupai Falls. This waterfall is also within the bounds of Grand Canyon National Park. People travel from thousands of miles away, with months or years of planning in advance in order to get a photo-op with the brilliantly turquoise blue waters of Havasupai Falls. The draws of the falls for tourists brings attention to one aspect of the cultural significance of the water but misses a central point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listened to an episode titled “Resiliency” of a podcast called “Podship Earth” in which Jared Blumenfeld, the California Secretary for Environmental Protection, interviews Rochelle Tilousi, a Havasupai woman. Jared asks about the meaning of the water to her and her tribe, and in response she shares that “in one of the creation stories, the Havasupai people came to be through a drop of spring water and the sunshine coming into the woman who gave birth to the Havasupai people…the water is very sacred to our tribe.” Verbally acknowledging that the water is sacred to the Havasupai people is perhaps the most justice words can do to illustrate the importance of this water to the Havasupai. However, I would like to pause on this example to set the stage for a continuous theme throughout this essay. There is one side of Nixon’s idea of slow violence (Nixon, 2011) that white settlers have inflicted upon Native Americans in which natural resources have been gradually diverted away, leading to agricultural decline on reservations (see Chapter 4). However, one could coin “spiritual violence” as another form of slow violence that has been harmful to Native Americans. From a capitalistic viewpoint, one only needs as much water as one requires, thus, the rest must be profited off of one way or another, whether through tourism or exportation. Introducing these elements also introduces potentially hazardous environmental impacts, like in the case of the Havasupai, things as simple as an abundance of litter, to larger threats like the quality of the water and if it is be safe for the Havasupai children to swim in. Though those are valid concerns, they need not be required in order to bring attention to the importance of preserving land and resources. Many environmental perspectives lack sufficient protections for the sacrality of natural resources that many Native Americans hold. When a resource is designated as religious artifact, that ought to be sufficient motivation for protecting the resource. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Desert Wasn’t Always a Desert&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, a paradigm shift about the desert and its relationship with water, told by a story occurring over millions of years. Arizona, yes Arizona, or at least significant parts of it, was probably buried underneath the sea many millions of years ago during the Paleozoic Era (National Park Sevice). Now, the closest thing Arizona has to an ocean requires a six-hour drive west to California, or four-hour drive south to Puerto Peñasco, Mexico. (That is, with one small exception. The Biosphere are the University of Arizona in Tucson includes a simulated ocean (Lee, 2014). With climate change hard at work, it is predicted that Arizona will become a coastal state in one thousand years (Stern, 2015) after sea-levels increase by 30 meters and swells the Colorado River Delta (Stern, 2015). Though visions of an Arizonan beach might sound enticing, Stern points out that “lying on the beach might not be fun if it’s 130 degrees,” given the correlation of rising sea-levels and rising temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;{A shell found in the desert near Scottsdale, Arizona. Traces of Arizona’s oceanic past still remain. Or maybe this was a coincidence ¯(ツ)/¯}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./desert_shell.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;desert-shell&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the layman might not know about Phoenix in its present state is that a huge quantity of water is stored underground beneath Phoenix. Phoenix’s nickname is the “Valley of the Sun” but, ironically, the fact that it is a valley makes it a great place for a different element: water. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomsen &amp;#x26; Baldys remind us that rain is scarce in Phoenix, whereas evaporation happens at incredible rates under the desert sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    “...average annual precipitation is about 8 in., and the average annual lake precipitation is about 75 in… irrigated agriculture, which became a prominent industry in the 1940’s, uses most of the available surface water and between 1 and 2 million acre-feet of ground water each year&quot; (Thomsen &amp; Baldys, 1985).
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the ground water that might be hidden from Phoenicians’ consciouses is anything but idle or unutilized. As cited, the amount of ground water that was extracted for agricultural use almost 50 years ago was great in magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;{Graph in Thomsen &amp;#x26; Baldys’ USGS report illustrating ground-water pumpage in the Phoenix area from 1915-1981}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./thomsen_graph.png&quot; alt=&quot;ground-water-graph&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomsen, B. W., and Stanley Baldys. Ground-water conditions in and near the Gila River Indian Reservation, south-central Arizona. No. 85-4073. 1985.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nixon, Rob. Slow Violence and the Environmentalism of the Poor. Harvard University Press, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geologic Evolution of the Parashant: Grand Canyon-Parashant National Monument Arizona. National Park Service. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nps.gov/para/learn/nature/geologic-evolution-of-the-parashant.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.nps.gov/para/learn/nature/geologic-evolution-of-the-parashant.htm&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee, J. L. Why Are Scientists Building an “Ocean” in the Middle of a Desert? National Geographic. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/science/article/140718-biosphere-gulf-california-environment-ocean-science&quot;&gt;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/science/article/140718-biosphere-gulf-california-environment-ocean-science&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stern, Ray. Climate Change to Transform Arizona Into Coastal State. Phoenix New Times. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phoenixnewtimes.com/news/climate-change-to-transform-arizona-into-coastal-state-7798437&quot;&gt;https://www.phoenixnewtimes.com/news/climate-change-to-transform-arizona-into-coastal-state-7798437&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Benji's Breakfast Bash]]></title><description><![CDATA[{A Central Arizona Project canal transporting water from the Colorado River elsewhere in Arizona}(This photograph is in the public domain…]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoys-snacks//breakfast-bash/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoys-snacks//breakfast-bash/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h6&gt;{A Central Arizona Project canal transporting water from the Colorado River elsewhere in Arizona}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This photograph is in the public domain)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sources (Present Day)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50% of Phoenix water comes from surface and groundwater from the Salt River Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About 40% comes from the Colorado River via the Central Arizona Project &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About 10% is pumped from wells or is recycled wastewater&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100% of the City of Phoenix’s water supply is disinfected using chlorine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason Phoenix presently relies on very little groundwater is rooted in the past. Phoenix withdrew excessive amounts of water while it was rapidly growing, that is, until the groundwater crisis was known and a 1980 reform bill shifted the focus to the Central Arizona Project (Powell, 2008).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Canals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canals in Phoenix are everywhere. And they kind of always have been. The Hohokam, also known as the Huhugam, (the likely ancestors of the Pima) built an intricate canal system to support their agriculture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When manifest destiny brough white settlers to the area, the early days of Phoenix were also characterized by canals, some of which have been preserved for an unbelievable amount of time. The name “Phoenix” originates from those original canals. &lt;em&gt;Huhugam&lt;/em&gt; means “those who have gone” because of their still unexplained, sudden disappearance. Thus, the Phoenix bird was resemblant of the “rebirth of a city from an ancient and abandoned culture” whose traces left behind were canals (Fast Facts on a sign on the GRIR).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    “…minerals and algae that collect in the canals that transport our surface water along to Phoenix’s water treatment plants.  The algae is removed during the treatment process, but much like a bouquet of roses that has not been in a room for hours, you still may be able to smell it” (City of Phoenix, FAQ).
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FAQ: How can I improve the taste and odor of my water?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    “To improve taste and odor place a slice of lemon in your water” (City of Phoenix, FAQ).
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;{Me running on the Arizona Canal}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./canal_run.gif&quot; alt=&quot;canal-run&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While browsing historic canal photographs, I came across an interesting comment on an article about canals in Phoenix. The poster, Kevin, describes how he ran cross country for Maryvale High School in the 90s and put in many training miles on the Grand Canal. He went on to say that grapefruit trees alongside the canal were the perfect spot for a mid-run snack. This brings back a wave of nostalgia for me, as I have also run hundreds of miles on the canals and have also picked a citrus fruit or two during a run. Then he proposes that Phoenix’s canals are being underutilized. He compares them to Venice and San Antonio, wondering why Phoenix didn’t follow in their footsteps and place large buildings facing the canals. It’s true that all of he canals I’ve ever run on are outlined by residential streets that are trying to hide from the canal if anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;{Terminus of the Agua Fria River, just North of Lake Pleasant and the New Waddell Dam that created the lake. If you look closely, you can see cattle walking in the river bed up ahead.}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./agua_fria_terminus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;agua-fria&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &quot;My father&apos;s reasons for opposing the dam were what we would today call ecological...with his forecasts about the consequences of the dam—most of which, incidentally, have proven correct—was a lone voice in the wilderness.&quot;  &lt;i&gt;--Leila Ahmed in her memoir (Ahmed, 1999), daughter of the chairman of the Nile Water Control Board&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahmed, Leila. A border passage. Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1999.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frequently Asked Questions Drinking Water. City of Phoenix. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phoenix.gov/waterservices/envservices/drinking-water/faqs#:~:text=Drinking%20Water%E2%80%8B,water%20treatment%20and%20distribution%20systems&quot;&gt;https://www.phoenix.gov/waterservices/envservices/drinking-water/faqs#:~:text=Drinking%20Water%E2%80%8B,water%20treatment%20and%20distribution%20systems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Powell, James Lawrence. Dead pool: Lake Powell, global warming, and the future of water in the West. Univ of California Press, 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where Does Phoenix Water Come From? City of Phoenix. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phoenix.gov/waterservices/resourcesconservation/yourwater&quot;&gt;https://www.phoenix.gov/waterservices/resourcesconservation/yourwater&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Power Protein Pancakes]]></title><description><![CDATA[I took all of these videos in the immediate proximity of my house on January 20th, 2017 on a very rainy desert day. Note: This page will…]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoys-snacks//Power Protein Pancakes/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoys-snacks//Power Protein Pancakes/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I took all of these videos in the immediate proximity of my house on January 20th, 2017 on a very rainy desert day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: This page will probably take a long time to load and may not work on a mobile device. My apologies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./roof_rain.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Cactus&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./street_gutter.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Cactus&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./feet_water.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Cactus&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./lemon_tree.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Cactus&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./mesquite.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Cactus&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./oasis.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Cactus&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./onyx_oasis.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Cactus&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./palos_verde_drops.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Cactus&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./pool_drops.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Cactus&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./prickly_drop.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Cactus&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./river_rocks.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Cactus&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hen's Tasty Tilapia]]></title><description><![CDATA[{Aerial view of the Gila River running through the Gila River Indian Reservation. Upon closer examination, canals are also visible…]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoys-snacks//Hen&apos;s Tasty Tilapia/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoys-snacks//Hen&apos;s Tasty Tilapia/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h6&gt;{Aerial view of the Gila River running through the Gila River Indian Reservation. Upon closer examination, canals are also visible.}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Dicklyon, CC BY-SA 4.0 &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0&quot;&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0&lt;/a&gt;, via Wikimedia Commons)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Gila River &amp;#x26; Gila River Indian Community (GRIC)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two Native American Tribes call the Gila River Indian Reservation (GRIR) home: the Pimas (Akimel O’Odham) and the Maricopas (PeePosh). As of 2018, 13,577 people live within the borders of the GRIR, just southwest of Phoenix, with many more members of the community living elsewhere (Gila River Primary Care Area Statistical Profile, 2019). &lt;em&gt;Akimel O’Odham&lt;/em&gt; means “The River People” (Informational sign on the GRIR).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gila River spans the entire width of Arizona and more, traveling from New Mexico across the Arizona border westward until it meets the western Arizona border near Yuma and joins the Colorado River. The Gila River is not just any old river—it is a mighty river that Arizona depends upon. Its watershed covers over more than half of the state, totaling to almost 60,000 square miles, and the river itself totals 570 miles in length in Arizona (Celebrating Arizona’s Rivers). The Gila River could be characterized as the liaison between the Colorado River and the rest of Arizona’s waters; the Gila is the receptacle of nearly all significant Arizonan Rivers, and then transports that water to the Colorado, which then flows into the Gulf of California (Celebrating Arizona’s Rivers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;{Visualizing the enormity of the Gila River Watershed, pictured in green}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./gila_watershed.png&quot; alt=&quot;gila-watershed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Kmusser, CC BY-SA 2.5 &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5&quot;&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5&lt;/a&gt;, via Wikimedia Commons)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gila may sound like a raging river that brings prosperity throughout central Arizona from one end of the state to the other, but as someone who has lived in close proximity to the Gila, the expansiveness of the river was shocking information. To me, all rivers in central Arizona are dried up, disappeared. I drive by the Salt River all the time, but that is not a river—only a skeleton of what once was a river. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same applies for the Gila. Once an abundant river, it is now showing clear evidence of being severely tampered with over the past century. So much so that most segments of the river do not contain any water at all most of the year. In fact, only 162 of the 570 miles, or about 28 percent, of the Arizonan Gila river flow year-round, a phenomenon that has only recently occurred (Celebrating Arizona’s Rivers). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, tragically, the same story arc also applies for the people native to the GRIR. Once a thriving agricultural community, the diversion of their waters for “public” use completely upended their way of life. No longer able to grow their own, nourishing food, the U.S. government sent in unhealthy and unsatisfying canned foods as aid (Gila River Indian Community - History). The GRIC is subject to a massive amount of academic research because, in 2008, the community had the highest rate of diabetes in the world (Brown, 2008). In 2018, the GRIC had a median household income of $18,666, with 48.5% of community members living below the Federal Poverty Line (Gila River Primary Care Area Statistical Profile, 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Water Battles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The devestating impacts of white settlement in Arizona on the GRIR have been known for over 100 years. Thomsen &amp;#x26; Baldys cite Olberg, 1919, relaying that diversion of Gila River water by white settlers began in the 1860s (in alignment with the Homestead Act of 1862) as well as mentioning the huge surge in ground-water pumping in the 1940s. USGS report on south-central Arizona, including the entirety of the GRIR, Thanks to the Arizona Water Settlement Act of 2004, the GRIC once again has rightful ownership of the water on their land. This act came after 117 years of fighting for their water rights. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &quot;It is not stated in the act of Congress how much of this land it is desired to provide water for. It would not be possible with all the water supply of the river to irrigate more than half of it, but of course this would be vastly more than the actual requirements for the sustenance of the Indian, which Mr. Davis estimates to be about an acre and a half of ground per capital&quot; &lt;i&gt;-CONDITIONS AND COST OF WATER STORAGE FOR IRRIGATION ON THE GILA RIVER, ARIZONA. 56th Congress, 1st session.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Water Elsewhere on the GRIR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;{Firebird Lake on the Gila River Indian Reservation in Chandler, AZ. The boat-racing lake was opened in 1975 to bring jobs into the community.}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./firebird_lake.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;firebird-lake&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This photograph is in the public domain)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water takes many other forms on the GRIR, including but not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;golf course&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;casino (running water, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;resort pool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;manmade creek&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spa &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;canals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Full circle?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the ammenities on the GRIR, like the incoming soccer stadium for Phoenix’s professional soccer team, are very intentional money generators, and not in the traditional, capitalistic sense. Ironically, the motivation of all these new developments is to get to a place where the community has the “infrastructure to return the majority of the Gila River Indian Community to the thriving farmland it once was” (Informational sign on the GRIR). This goal is set to be accomplished by 2030.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;{Water is pumped in and dyed turquoise to create the artificial creek that winds around the Wild Horse Pass Hotel and Casino interpretive trail}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./casino_creek.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;casino_creek&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Gila River as Art&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;{Along the Gila Valley by Eugene Kingman. Acrylic. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usbr.gov/museumproperty/art/ekingman2.html&quot;&gt;US Bureau of Reclamation&lt;/a&gt;}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./gila_painting.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;gila-painting&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;{A one-minute film demonstrating the olfactory, visual, and audio experience created by using water from the Gila River in New Mexico}&lt;/h6&gt;

          &lt;div
            class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot;
            style=&quot;padding-bottom: 56.25%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 1.0725rem&quot;
          &gt;
            &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/230196025&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen style=&quot;
            position: absolute;
            top: 0;
            left: 0;
            width: 100%;
            height: 100%;
          &quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/230196025&quot;&gt;Fragrant Mist &amp;amp; Video Projection Tests&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/stephendirkes&quot;&gt;stephen dirkes&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
          
&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brown, J. J. (2008). When Our Water Returns: Gila River Indian Community and Diabetes1. Evergreen State College: National Science Foundation under Grant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bureau of Women’s and Children’s Health, Arizona Department of Health Services. (2019). Gila River Indian Community Primary Care Area (PCA) (pp. 1–4) [Statistical Profile]. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.azdhs.gov/documents/prevention/health-systems-development/data-reports-maps/primary-care/pinal/73.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.azdhs.gov/documents/prevention/health-systems-development/data-reports-maps/primary-care/pinal/73.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Celebrating Arizona’s Rivers - August 2012: The Gila River. kjzz.org and the University of Arizona Water Resources Research Center. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.kjzz.org/s3fs-public/GilaRiverFactSheet.pdf&quot;&gt;https://media.kjzz.org/s3fs-public/GilaRiverFactSheet.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gila River Indian Community. (n.d.-b). History. Retrieved June 7, 2019, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gilariver.org/index.php/about/history&quot;&gt;http://www.gilariver.org/index.php/about/history&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple signs along the scenic trail near Wild Horse Pass Casino on the Gila River Indian Reservation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olberg, C. R., 1919, Report on the San Carlos Irrigation project: Indians of the United States. Hearings before the Committee on Indian Affairs, House of Representatives, 66th Congress, 1st session, v. 2, appendix A., p. 1-1-2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomsen, B. W., and Stanley Baldys. Ground-water conditions in and near the Gila River Indian Reservation, south-central Arizona. No. 85-4073. 1985.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Epilogue]]></title><description><![CDATA[{The epitome of the desert/water contrast: snow-laden cacti on the way from Phoenix to Flagstaff, AZ}Going through my personal archives…]]></description><link>https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoys-snacks//Message from Mandy/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://mandydavis.github.io/smccoys-snacks//Message from Mandy/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h6&gt;{The epitome of the desert/water contrast: snow-laden cacti on the way from Phoenix to Flagstaff, AZ}&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going through my personal archives proved to be an unexpected journey through water and time. That is, before this project I knew there was a certain significance to water in the desert. What I did not realize is how present water has been in my desert life. Not only does it sustain me, it is also omnipresent. I could look through nearly any period of my life and find photographs of water in Arizona. This may seem like a contradiction, but if this project has demonstrated anything it is that water is both scarce (sometimes) and, without doubt, sacred.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The politics of water are not something I was aware of until college. I had lived my whole life in close proximity to the Gila River, but never knew its story until I studied a different aspect of the Gila River Indian Reservation for a class my Sophomore year. Growing up, I had heard that diabetes was a serious problem on the reservation, but no one ever explained how that diabetes rate came to be. It was by design, just like the water diversions that caused it. Water holds secrets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its secretive fashion, water in the desert holds a special significance that draws in the fascination of someone passing by. Water in the desert has always been instantly available in abundance from my sink, but upon reflection, I have also always viewed water in desert as a scarce, sacred miracle. For that is the reason I believe I have so much photographic evidence throughout my years of living in the desert. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love when it rains in Phoenix, and I hate when it rains in Evanston. Water is different in the desert.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>